Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ambareesh-murty-b35803 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Product Management Management Strategy

Ambareesh Murty

Founder, Pepperfry Mumbai

Summary

Over 14 years of general management experience in the FMCG, financial services & Internet industries.

Began my career with Cadbury in Sales and Marketing, followed by a stint with Prudential ICICI AMC (now ICICI Prudential) as VP Marketing & Customer Service.

Signed up for a personal career adventure from 2003-2005, when I ran a financial training & business consulting firm in Bangalore. Joined eBay in December 2005 and was with eBay till June 2011. Now an entrepreneur in the Indian online space.

I hold a B.E. in from the Delhi College of Engineering and a MBA from the Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta.

Specialties: General Management, Marketing, Sales Management, Corporate Strategy

Experience

Pepperfry

Founder

July 2011 - Present (9 years 2 months)

Mumbai Area, India

eBay India, Philippines and Malaysia

5 years 7 months

Country Manager

March 2008 - June 2011 (3 years 4 months)

Country Manager from Mar 2008 - June 2011.

In the last 3 1/2 years, eBay has seen rapid growth and further enhanced market leadership across these markets. This was driven by strong product and process localization and a great team dynamic.

As an active industry contributor, I also served as the Vice Chairman of the Internet & Mobile Association of India (IAMAI) through 2009-10.

Director - Marketplace Development & User Experience December 2005 - February 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Jan 2007 - Feb 2008

Along with my 'supply side' responsibilities I also took on the leadership of the User Experience group, accountable for Operations, payments, user retention and engagement.

Dec 2005 - Dec 2006

Led the 'supply side' functions of the eBay India marketplace. Managed seller acquisition & development, marketplace pricing, category insights and the global trade business.

Britannia Industries

Marketing Manager - Mass Markets

June 2005 - December 2005 (7 months)

Responsible for the segment P&L and strategy definition.

Managed communication development, retail strategy and innovation.

Origin Resources

Founder

December 2003 - May 2005 (1 year 6 months)

The business fulfilled the need for formal traning content development and delivery in the emerging Indian Asset Management space.

Origin Resources helped train financial advisors and channel intermediaries, and help set up advisor networks by providing turnkey advisor acquisition, training and empanelment solutions to Indian Mutual Funds.

Levi Strauss India Ltd.

Brand Leader - Levi's

August 2003 - December 2003 (5 months)

Responsibilities included product development and marketing and retail strategies for the Levi's brand.

ICICI Prudential AMC Ltd

VP - Marketing & Customer Service

October 2001 - August 2003 (1 year 11 months)

Led brand, product and customer service strategy and implementation.

Cadbury India
Brand Manager
June 1996 - October 2001 (5 years 5 months)

Responsible for Cadbury's flagship brands, Dairy Milk and Five Star.

Conceptualized and launched Cadbury 'Temptations', one of India's most

successful product launches in 2001.

In the course of my Cadbury career, have also managed new product development and the gifting segment.

I started my Cadbury career in sales as ASM - Kerala.

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta MBA, Management · (1994 - 1996)

Delhi College of Engineering B.E., Civil Engineering · (1990 - 1994)